Downloaded @ subs4free.club
www.titlovi.com
Transcript by sub. Trader
BERING SEA
80 MILES WEST OF ALASKA
DINOSAURS IN OUR WORLD
Dinosaurs are in our world.
And with every confrontation we learn
more about this frightening new reality.
How did we get here?
It's been three decades
since the deadly events of Jurassic Park,
and we've yet to find a way
for these animals to live safely among us.
After the devastating eruption
of Isla Nublar's long dormant volcano,
those who survived
were transported to the mainland.
Many of the larger predators
were captured,
but the remaining creatures
scattered here, in Big Rock National Park.
While most remained in the wild,
those who made their way to civilization
struggled to adapt
to unfamiliar conditions.
Local authorities have warned,
the animals are unpredictable,
and when hungry, extremely violent.
As the dinosaurs spread across boarders,
a global black market has risen.
Scorn, you suck pathetic loser!
To combat the growing threat
of illegal poachers
the US Congress awarded sole
collection rights to the global giant -
Biosyn Genetics.
At Biosyn, we're dedicated to the idea
that dinosaurs can teach us
more about ourselves.
CEO Lewis Dodgson has created
a sanctuary in Italy's Dolomite Mountains
where he hopes to study
the dinosaurs ancient immune system
for unique pharmaceutical properties.
While Biosyn believes we can handle
genetic power responsibly,
the public remains skeptical.
Some note that these government contracts
have led to massive spikes
in Biosyn's profits.
And rumors persist of a human clone
who mysteriously disappeared
leading to a world's wide search.
Some believe she's genetically identical
to Charlotte Lockwood,
deceased daughter of Jurassic Park
co-founder Benjamin Lockwood.
Now that we brought these animals
back from extinction,
can we face the consequences?
Are we responsible for them,
or should they be left
to fend for themselves?
As we adapt to an ever-changing world,
we must find answers to these questions.
For their safety as well as for our own.
SAW RIDGE CATTLE CO.
NEVADA
We are inside
the illegal breeding facility.
The juveniles are kept in cages
to keep cost down. It's medieval.
Claire.
Why do you think he's separated
from the rest?
I don't think he's gonna make it.
No. What are you doing? We report this.
The DFW takes days to investigate.
We can save this one now.
It's all good. It's all good, buddy.
Okay, here we go.
Nope. No!
- The head.
- Yeah.
Okay, yeah.
Okay, come on, let's go.
- Hold on!
- To what?
TRESPASSING
KEEP OUT
Claire, we're gonna get shot!
No, Back, no!
Oh, shit!
- Everybody good?
- No!
Okay, so I think we get this one
to the DFW, and then we hit them again.
Yeah, you saw that breeding ground, right?
We're done.
I got a call last week. It's a real job.
Something I can do to effectively
change things. I gotta take it.
They need us.
Are you saving these dinosaurs
because they need us
or are you saving them
to absolve yourself?
- Claire.
- I mean this is crazy.
Claire, you're doing the right thing.
But this isn't a way
to go about it anymore.
Honestly you need someone
who's good at being shot at.
Aren't you and Owen
still like a weird thing?
- It's not that weird.
- He didn't mean "weird." No.
He meant, like "surprising."
SIERRA NEVADA MOUNTAINS
Let's bring them home!
Okay, come here.
Okay.
We're gonna get you someplace safe.
Here you go. Here you go.
Hey!
- Where have you been?
- Nowhere.
- What are you burning?
- Nothing. Just some old blankets.
You sure you didn't go past the bridge?
That's the look you give me
when you think I'm lying.
- Are you?
- No.
Maisie, you're literally
looking everywhere but here.
I said I didn't go past the bridge.
Maisie, can we start over?
I know, Claire, there are people out there
who would do anything to find me.
I'm not angry, that means
you don't have to be angry.
I'm not angry.
- I can take care of myself.
- Hey!
It's okay for us to depend on each other.
That's what people do.
How would I know what people do?
The only people I've spoken to
in the past four years are you both.
Besides, I'm not even a real person anyway.
What?
I was made from someone else. I'm not me.
You're the only you who ever was.
What? What that, like really corny?
It was so corny.
- Can we keep that between us?
- Can't promise that.
- Hey, kid. Sorry I'm late.
- Hi.
You smell like horses.
- Oh, you like that, do you?
- I do. Yeah.
Okay.
I'm gonna make dinner.
Everything okay?
She went into town again.
Oh, this kid...
Did you talk to her?
I tried.
I'll talk to her.
Cut away from yourself.
- Stone cold.
- Right?
- I would not mess with her.
- No way.
Listen, kiddo, we should probably talk
about you going into town.
I don't think you understand
how bad it is being trapped here.
You're not trapped here,
we just don't trust people.
No, you just don't trust me.
And then you expect me to trust you.
- Why can't I have any freedom?
- Because you can't.
- That went great.
- What is happening?
- She's 14.
- Yeah.
You remember what that was like.
I do.
We can't keep her here forever.
If we don't figure this out she's gonna go
a lot further than the bridge.
If they find her
we never gonna see her again.
We gotta protect her. That's our job.
That's what we are gonna do.
Protect her how? By locking her inside?
She's got questions.
You know, questions we can't answer.
She wants to know who she is.
Who Charlotte Lockwood was.
Tracked Grady to his house.
You were right.
Raptor's got a juvenile.
But listen, there's something else.
I found that girl you've been after.
WEST TEXAS
Thanks for coming.
Wasn't sure whom to call.
They said Wildlife didn't even want
to see it if it wasn't a dinosaur.
Yeah, well, they get all the attention.
You guy wanna vary the sampling plots
a 100 yards each.
- These are your students?
- Yeah.
We've been looking into the impact
of industrial farming on the environment.
So, this is right up our alley.
They hit 60 fields in the county.
You seen anything like this before?
No, not like this.
They've been leaving degrading fields
all across the Midwest.
First, these big companies
try to kill off all the insects.
Now this.
Is that your land?
That's the Bennetts corn.
The locust didn't eat that.
- You plant the same seed as the Bennetts?
- No.
We are independent.
They use Biosyn seed.
Yeah, I bet they do.
You say you caught a live one?
UTAH
Okay, let it out slow.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Easy!
Why do we dig?
Because paleontology is science,
and science is about the truth.
And there is truth in these rocks.
Grant!
You gonna wanna see this.
Ellie Sattler.
Alan Grant.
You look the same.
And this place is so...
So... you.
I'm sorry. If I'd known
you were coming I would...
Can I get you something? A bear? Or...
Maybe not at 10 a.m.
But, ice tea?
Tea, yeah! Tea, I can do that.
Saw a lot of tourists on the way in.
All the funding dried up, so...
Somebody's gotta pay for all of this.
Thank you.
I read your articles about soil science
and regenerative farming. It was great.
Thanks.
Could be grounds for some hope
for a change.
How are your kids?
Amazing. Grown, it's shocking.
They're both in college,
can you believe that?
And Mark?
It's over.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
It's okay. I'm back to me, and my work.
And now it's...
- That's great.
- That's good. It is.
I'm alone at last.
Exciting times.
Yeah, I'm living that Alan Grant life.
- It's just...
- Can be lonely.
So free.
Ellie...
You didn't come out all this way
just to catch up now, did you?
It's a locust.
Mandibles, wings, thorax, but...
God, the size of it is massive.
It has genes that had been extinct
since the Cretaceous.
And swarms of them are decimating
crops from Iowa to Texas.
Terrifying, right?
Started as a few hundred.
It could be millions
by the end of this summer.
If they keep going there will be no grain
to feed chickens, cattle.
The entire food chain would collapse.
Well, it's clearly designed,
but why would anyone do that?
None of the crops they're eating
are Biosyn seed.
Biosyn.
You're saying Biosyn made this?
It would not shock me that they wanna
control the world's food supply.
- Not before a few millions starve.
- Now, what is that saying?
"We are three meals away from anarchy."
If we don't stop them
you can pick your last three meals.
So, why are you bringing it to me?
I need concrete evidence
Biosyn's responsible for all this.
I need to go to their sanctuary
and get DNA from another locust there.
But I need a witness.
Alan...
You command respect. People believe you.
Yeah.
You know why I'm here?
It's quiet. I'm done with all of that.
Are you? Okay.
Well, I'm sorry, Alan. Nobody gets
that luxury anymore, not even you.
And you know what?
You are the one I trust.
This Biosyn's sanctuary is what,
a hundred miles from anywhere?
How would you even get in there?
I got an invite
from their in-house philosopher.
Seems there's a lot of money
in being a chaotician these days.
And he just happen to invite you
out of the blue?
He said there were things I'd wanna see.
You coming or what?
U.S. WILDLIFE RELOCATION FACILITY
PENNSYLVANIA
Come on!
It's clear!
Every animal captured on the mainland
comes through here
before shipping out
to Biosyn's sanctuary in Dolomites.
We give them the medical attention
and make sure they live healthy.
- So much security.
- Those are just the ones you see.
A lot of shady types out there
want these guys.
Your plane is just fueling up.
Biosyn's a tough invite,
you guys must know somebody.
- Do you mind if I...
- Of course.
Hi there.
Follow me.
We rescued these guys from an illegal
breeding farm in Nevada a few weeks ago.
Shut the whole place down. Anonymous tip.
Good girl. Yes, yes.
Alan, you never get used to it.
- Take care. Thank you.
- Bye.
Hey.
You look just like Blue.
Is she your mother?
This? You wanna try it?
Okay.
Maisie, don't move..
Hey, girl. Staying out of trouble?
She had a baby. That's impossible.
- Back up.
- She won't hurt us, right?
Oh, you damn right she will. Just breathe.
If you don't she'll think you're scared.
I am scared.
She doesn't need to know that.
Her nest has got to be nearby.
Maisie get inside.
- I'm coming with you.
- What did I just say?
- We gotta move.
- Not yet, we need the girl.
Hey, what's up?
Maisie?
Where are you going?
You can't keep me here,
you're not my mother.
She's leaving the house.
- Time to go!
- Come on let's go!
Who are you?
Claire!
They found her.
What? Who are they?
Poachers, I've seen them around.
Leader's a real shit heel.
He must have recognized me,
followed me here.
- Where is she?
- Go get the truck.
Oh, my God.
Owen!
Hey! No.
They took her kid too.
I am gonna get her back.
I promise you that.
Come on. I know whom to call.
CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY
DANGEROUS SPECIES DIVISION
This year, man. What's next?
Historically? Darkness, blood,
reign of fire.
I think frogs.
We're not gonna be around
for much longer anyway.
These locusts in Nebraska
are about to wrap it up.
They're in the corn, wheat.
Basically whole of our food
and our food's food, so...
We can say goodbye to this.
- Hello?
- Franklin, it's me. You're at work?
You're kinda subject of interest
around here,
so I can't really be talking to you.
Come, on, I'm in trouble.
I really need your help. Please.
Yeah, and I could lose my job,
and you know I'm not qualified
to do anything else.
We're outside.
Let me talk to him.
- Is that him?
- That's him.
Name's Rainn Delacourt.
A real piece of work.
What did he take?
Something we care about very much.
Oh, shit. I told you somebody
would come looking for her.
You can't just take a person, Claire.
- I had no choice.
- Not in the eyes of the law.
This guy is not the "law."
Tell us how to find him.
What did you guys call me from?
We have a man on the inside
of Delacourt's operation.
There's an exchange in Malta
sometime tomorrow, cash for cargo.
Is she with him?
There's no mention, but we have people
on the ground already.
One of them you know.
A lot of us got recruited by the CIA
after the Park went down.
Barry's French intelligence now.
- I need to talk to him.
- You can't just call him. He's deep cover.
Look, once we make the bust in Malta
our guys will see if Delacourt knows
where she is.
Our guys, not you.
Promise me you won't go in there
with your vest and mess everything up.
Why would I do that?
Look, you guys are both crazy.
But you seem like you're good parents,
or whatever you're trying to be.
She's lucky to have you.
Don't get killed, okay?
I think we're almost there.
Yeah.
BIOSYN SANCTUARY
DOLOMITE MOUNTAINS, ITALY
Dr. Sattler, Dr. Grant,
Ramsay Cole, Communications.
Oh, hey.
I have to warn you,
everyone is so excited to have you.
You guys are absolute legends around here.
You must be confusing us
with somebody else.
You know, It's great that you guys
are still so close to Dr. Malcolm.
Sometimes you meet your heroes
and they disappoint you,
but he's exactly the way
you'd want him to be.
Such motility of thought, it's incredible.
How much time did you spend with him?
Well, I know that was sarcastic,
but honestly, not enough.
Please, after you. And watch your head.
So, Biosyn bought this land for the amber
deposits back in the nineties,
but we've managed to turn into
a safe haven
for about 20 displaced species.
The first generation came from Sorna.
Most of the Nublar dinosaurs are here too.
Took Fish and Wildlife three years
to catch the T-Rex.
The T-Rex is here?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Arrived just before you guys.
Aerial deterrent system - active.
Restricted aerial space.
Protects the airborne life.
Keeps the Pterosaurs below 500 feet.
Airborne?
Is that Dreadnoughtus?
What?
Beautiful, right?
Her name means "fear nothing."
I guess you know that.
- What do they graze on?
- All thorn and fern.
All indigenous, nothing stocked,
except for the deer population.
It's a great mesenchyme species
for the apex predator.
- The apex predator?
- Giganotosaurus.
At least for now.
You don't let people in there, right?
No. Our research outposts
are connected completely underground.
If we have to we can just
herd the animals remotely
using neural implant that sends
electrical signals directly to the brain.
Like shocks?
No, like signals.
Does it strike you as a little bit...
- Cruel?
- Cruel.
Do you know how much voltage was
in the electric fences at Jurassic Park?
Yeah.
Please join Dr. Ian Malcolm at noon
in the lecture hall
for the "Ethics of genetic power."
God, everyone's so young.
Well, It is part of our ethos
to track the best and brightest.
Doctors. Respected, renowned.
Dr. Sattler, Dr. Grant. Hi.
Wow, this is big, I'm Lewis.
- Dodgson. Yeah.
- Hi.
- You're Lewis Dodgson?
- I am. How do you do?
We didn't expect to actually see you here.
Well, I wouldn't be anywhere else.
- Would you?
- No.
I mean, people you see here
are changing the world.
Would you mind if we...
It would mean a lot if...
Do you wanna...
Oh, great. Thank you so much.
That's good. That's good. Thanks.
So, you are going to see
some remarkable things today.
We're unlocking the true power
of the genome.
We're this close, believe me.
- You'll make a fortune off that.
- No, it's not about money.
No, we've already identified
dozens of applications for Paleo DNA.
We're talking about cancer,
Alzheimer's, autoimmune.
We will be saving lives.
I bet.
Anyway, I wish I could take
you around myself, but...
So, you're in more than capable
hands with Ramsay.
He's basically a young me.
Only smarter and taller.
Do you have food?
- Like, one of my bars?
- Pardon?
No, never mind, I'll find something.
So, I wanna do more of this
later on if we...
Oh, we booked you on a private pod
for the trip out, so...
It's beautiful. You'll love it.
Through the caverns and everything.
You better hurry, Malcolm's on.
He's a bit of a contrarian,
but I like him.
He keeps us on our toes.
Anyway...
Thank you for being here, it's...
Okay, follow me, please.
What?
Human beings have no more right
to safety or liberty
than any other creature on this planet.
We not only lack dominion over nature,
we're subordinate to it.
And now here we are, with the opportunity
to rewrite life at our fingertips.
And just like with nuclear power,
nobody knew what to expect
with genetic engineering,
but they pressed
the button and hoped for the best.
Just like you are doing now.
Yep, you.
You control the future
of our survival on planet Earth.
According to you
the solution is genetic power.
But that same power
could devastate the food supply,
create new diseases,
alter the climate even further.
Unforeseen consequences occur.
And every time. Every single time
we all act surprised.
Because deep down I don't think
that any of us actually believe
that these dangers are real.
In order to instigate revolutionary change
we must transform human consciousness.
May am?
Very good. There you go.
I don't want to be rude to my friends.
Catch me on my way out. Thanks everybody.
Look at you. Look at me, and look at you.
Whoa, this is so trippy.
You look like you're doing well.
Well, I got five kids, you know,
whom I adore more than life itself, so...
expenses add up.
You? Alan, are you...
You have any family or?
No.
- I need to talk to you.
- I need to talk to you too, privately.
Do you two talk a lot?
He slid into my DMs.
- He did what?
- It's urgent, Ian.
- What did you do?
- Seven minutes to midnight stuff.
The doomsday clock might be
about out of time, but as they say,
it's always darkest
just before eternal nothingness.
What?
Locusts altered with Cretaceous Era DNA...
That's not my field.
But if these things continue to multiply
we're talking about cascading
system-wide effects, Ian.
- Gosh, that's a drag.
- What is the matter with you?
Why, is there something special
you want me to do?
How about give a damn?
Hey, I gave my opinion robustly for years.
As expected, the sum of our human
endeavors has led to our annihilation.
And the only play now
is to take the time we have left
and, you know, just like
we always do, squander it.
Honestly, Ian, that's bullshit.
Can I offer you guys some joe?
Tyler, please, two cappuccinos.
I don't want a cappuccino.
Well, I can do a cortado
or, like, macchiato?
Trust me, it's real tough that jet lag,
that's gonna perk you right up.
The locusts are a part of a larger project
called Hexapod Allies.
You were right about their regiment.
I just heard here a rumor six weeks ago.
I read your piece
on decadence and put two and two together.
- I was not raising my voice.
- You're beginning to.
It's what you're doing.
They proliferating wildly. They're lasting
three-four times longer than they should.
And all my models are pointing
toward a global ecological collapse, Ian.
Downstairs. Sub-level 6.
That's where they keep the locusts.
Look for a lab marked L4.
But wait, how are we ever
gonna get down there?
Hey, this looks so silky,
may I touch this blouse?
Sure.
You know what it is? Don't tell me.
- You won't know it.
- This is sustainable bamboo.
It is sustainable bamboo,
how did you know that?
Yeah, it's amazing.
I've got a cumin, I've got cinnamon,
I've got allspice, which is not
very popular. I've got five spice...
- Doctor.
- If you're into that kinda feel.
- Yeah.
- Let's talk milks, okay?
Soy Milk, yes?
No.
What just happened?
We're in.
Sub-level 6. Restricted.
Lewis, you're not listening to me.
The locusts prehistoric DNA has made them
stronger than they should be.
They're multiplying like crazy,
and they're not dying.
- What part of this don't you understand?
- Oh, I do understand.
- This is gonna be a global famine.
- Hey, we can't anticipate everything.
We need to eradicate the ones we released.
- What?
- All of them.
No. No.
Henry, we don't wanna cause a panic,
we want control.
These is no such thing.
When we're afraid what do we do?
What have we done before?
We follow through. That's what we do.
Right?
Right.
We found the girl. She's en route.
- Cost me a fortune.
- What?
Wait, you found her?
Yeah, found them both.
Her and the little Raptor.
Blue reproduced all on her own.
Just like you said.
You're so smart, Henry.
That's why this works.
You understand the value of these
creatures, you always have. I do too.
And we don't stop because of what,
little side project went south?
Hey.
If they trace the locusts back to us,
they come for the dinosaurs.
All your work gone.
Billions of dollars in assets gone.
Diamonds with no one to mine them.
You really think she's the solution?
Okay.
Everything involving the girl
goes through me, right?
Is she all right?
She better be.
She's the most valuable
intellectual property on the planet.
MALTA
- I said I'd call you.
- They land yet?
Second plane is incoming.
Who said anything about the second plane?
We flew them separately,
I'm not taking any chances.
And we'll need payment before delivery.
I didn't like what happened last time.
Okay. Okay.
Just call me when it's done.
You said I was going someplace safe.
You are.
Walk to the car.
No.
It's not a choice.
Fifty grand to fly
one little Raptor. Not bad.
What's with the girl?
Not your problem.
Pleasure doing business.
We're ready, let's go.
Owen.
Hi, Claire.
I thought you would've chosen
a quieter line of work.
I tried, my cousin and I opened a Cafe.
I lasted three weeks.
The way that world is headed
it's hard to look away.
Delacourt was hired by Soyona Santos,
a broker in the underground
dinosaur trade.
We don't have Intel on his cargo.
But once they make an exchange
we'll see what they know about your girl.
You can listen in, but promise me,
you will not make contact.
No.
All right. See you soon.
There's a big underground market
for dinosaurs now:
Europe, Middle East, Northern Africa.
It all comes through here.
Don't look at anyone, don't talk
to anyone. Just try to blend in.
I'm okay.
Still flying for Santos, huh?
You must need money.
What's it to you?
I've got cargo.
A thousand kilos
of dinosaur to Palermo.
I give you two thousand.
Two thousand? How much is there?
You lost?
You're American.
That makes us friends?
Listen, I just got here and...
No, that was not an invitation. Here.
A souvenir. Go back to the hotel.
You know, throw some bath salts
in the bath.
This place is not your vibe.
Wait.
- Look...
- Claire.
Claire, I know this must feel exotic,
but if you mess with the wrong person
down here you disappear.
You feel me?
Good luck, okay?
Wait.
- Wait.
- What is this?
- I need your help.
- I don't know you.
- I'm looking for someone.
- Don't do that.
She is all alone. Please.
- Is that your daughter?
- Yes.
Sorry, I can't get involved.
- I think I got him.
- Target on the move.
That's our undercover agent with him.
Claire, he's headed underground.
You see him?
Yeah, I've got him.
All right, let's go.
Hey, how you've been?
All units stay at bulls eye position.
This is Bravo 1. Primary target inside.
No sign of the girl.
My people say the Raptor arrived
in good condition.
You boys didn't cuck this up.
Call me amazed.
I do have another job for you.
Short, hot money's double.
What's the cargo?
Atrociraptors, thoroughbreds.
Trained to kill.
Kill who?
Whoever they're told.
Laser marks the target, they attach
the scent, don't stop till it's dead.
Inescapable.
Those idiots making hybrids
had it all wrong.
You can't engineer loyalty,
you have to nurture it.
Fifty thousand to fly them to Riyadh.
"In" or "out"?
She's not here.
Where are we going?
Almost there.
That's the draft. Let's go!
Everyone's down!
- Hands in the air!
- Drop your guns!
Delacourt, on the floor, now!
Get on the ground!
Delacourt, stay with!
Shit.
Get that truck out of here!
Santos, stay still!
We've lost Delacourt.
This is Bravo 1.
The truck approaching the underpass.
Go.
The girl. Where is she?
Where did they take her?
- Where is she?
- I don't know!
We handed her off to Santos.
I don't know where they took her after.
Claire, It's Santos, the one in white.
I'll find her.
Hold it.
- Let them out.
- What?
You heard me.
Damn.
Shit.
Claire, do you have her?
We had some trouble.
What kind?
The parents, Grady and Dearing.
They're here.
Can you take care of it?
Not for free.
Well, do it.
Okay, okay. Listen.
You don't use it on people.
Where's my daughter?
She wasn't yours to begin with.
Tell me.
Biosyn. They're taking her to Biosyn.
You missed her. She's gone.
Take my hand. Come on!
Hold on tight.
What?
Do you remember
how we used to get Raptors in the truck?
- Yeah.
- You're up.
- No.
The last minute dive roll.
I don't dive roll.
You'll be fine.
I never got the timing right.
- Now?
- Any minute. Any minute now.
Now?
No.
Now!
Freeze!
I'll fly us outta here.
Tell me where you wanna be dropped.
You ever flown to Biosyn?
Owen, they took her to Biosyn.
There's an airfield on the north side
of the island.
You're under arrest. Stay where you are.
Right!
Get down!
We made a lot of enemies. We gotta go.
He'll be here.
Out of time. Out of time.
There he is.
- Pull over.
- That's not how planes work.
Sub. T
Open the back.
Come on!
Hold on tight!
Still got it.
Kayla Watts.
You're welcome.
You look like you fly for Biosyn.
I'm gonna take that the way you meant it
and not the way it sounded.
I fly for whoever got a bag,
but we'll call this one a favor.
Those don't work. They broke.
I'll take y'all to Biosyn
but I can't promise it won't be dangerous.
You're willing to risk your life
for people you've never met?
You wanna ask questions or you wanna ride?
We'll take the ride.
So, this is our Habitat Development Lab.
A lot of exciting discoveries as of late.
We've brought back numerous species
in their purest form.
And I mean complete untouched genomes.
Like Moros intrepidus.
What?
Wow.
What about splicing DNA,
you know, creating new species?
No, Dr. Sattler, we don't do that here.
We like to think we're more evolved.
Okay, looks like we still have some
time left before your ride.
Would you guys like
to tour the facilities yourselves?
I mean, we could?
Yeah, why not.
Great, I'll meet you guys
at the Hyperloop Station 3
in about 30 minutes.
Elevators are down this hall. Not those.
Those lead you down to the sub-levels.
You need special clearance
to get down there.
Thirty minutes.
Here. Take this.
- You're ready?
- Yep.
I'm really sorry
that it had to happen this way.
Yep, that's what kidnappers say.
Claire should never have hidden you away.
You're way too important, Maisie.
You took her too?
Yeah.
We needed her to help us understand you.
Hey, Beta.
You okay?
Did you say Beta? Is that her name?
I gave it to her.
Beta's pretty special.
When we made Blue,
we used Monitor lizard DNA
to fill in the gaps in her genome.
Monitor lizards can reproduce
without a mate.
So, Beta and Blue
are genetically identical.
And that's what they have
in common with you and...
Charlotte.
What do you know about Charlotte?
She died.
A long time ago.
It broke my grandpa's heart.
So, he made me.
No, Maisie, actually he didn't.
Charlotte made you.
I'm so excited that everyone see
what we've been doing here.
There's new technology being made,
new science, like every day almost.
And it's great to be
in the center of that.
Charlotte lived on Site B
with all of us till the storm.
She'd loved dinosaurs.
Charlotte, be careful.
Yeah, I will.
She grew up around scientists.
And eventually...
she became one herself.
A butterfly flew into my office
this morning.
They say tiny things have huge impacts,
and I agree, wholeheartedly.
She was brilliant.
In ways that I'll never be.
In a metaphysics of identity,
can a replica truly be the original?
And if it's possible,
what makes it so?
I've lost my pen.
- Is that me?
- Yeah.
Just like Blue Charlotte was able
to have a child all by herself.
She created you with her own DNA.
So, I do have a mother.
Your grandfather didn't want anyone
to know the truth.
He was protecting her.
And you.
Are we the same?
You were.
When you were a baby Charlotte started
to show symptoms of a genetic disorder.
That's how she died.
She didn't know she had it
until after you were born.
- Do I have it too?
- No.
She changed your DNA.
She altered every cell in your body
to eradicate this disease.
No one on Earth has ever known
how to do that.
She fixed me.
Charlotte's discovery
is a part of you now.
Your DNA could change the world.
And I have to know how she did it.
But I just can't replicate her work.
If I could just study you
and Beta whose DNA
was never changed I could...
fix a terrible mistake that I've made.
What's kind of mistake?
Sub-level 6. Restricted.
Thanks for coming.
Which lab did Malcolm say?
L4.
This is it.
Okay, get in, get the sample, and get out.
And move slow. They could swarm
at even the slightest disturbance.
Orthoptera.
Who weeks.
Fully mature. This one.
Ready? Easy.
Okay, go.
What?
Go get it.
I that necessary?
What did you think was gonna happen?
I have to take a sample.
We need concrete evidence. This is it.
Alan, you said there was no time.
Can you get it?
Of course I can get it.
Easy.
Watch its legs.
Here we go.
They're still signaling between them.
- This is not good, Ellen.
- Almost got it.
How does she remain an asset, Henry,
if you're incriminating both of us
by showing her classified things
on the computer?
Charlotte Lockwood believed the methods
we used at Jurassic Park
could cure diseases.
She was right.
Having filled the gaps in Maisie's genome
with altered DNA,
she used a pathogen to deliver
the repaired sequence to every cell.
If I can re-purpose what she did,
I could change the locusts DNA,
eradicating them in a single generation.
Maisie and the baby Raptor
will provide the missing data.
Hey, you wanna get out of that?
What the...?
Got it.
Maisie!
Asset containment breach.
Please remain in your sessions.
Where's the key?
You okay?
Yeah, you?
Yeah.
You are Dr. Ellie Sattler and Alan Grant.
You were at Jurassic Park.
What are you doing here?
My name is Maisie Lockwood.
My grandpa knew John Hammond.
Hey.
We don't...
We don't work for Biosyn.
I can tell.
- We gotta get out of here.
- Yeah, we should go.
Okay, in and out.
We find your girl and go.
Tower, this N141, request to land
for freight delivery, over.
N141, negative,
we've been advised you're carrying
unauthorized passengers, over.
Copy that, Tower, be advised,
shipment is perishable.
We need immediate clearance.
It's an emergency, over.
But we said "no."
Negative, return to point of origin.
You seem to be breaking up.
Are you hearing me on your side?
Nice try, Kayla. They will down your bird.
Who is this? Is this Denise?
You do not want me
to start spilling secrets, Denise.
You remember Dubrovnik?
It's a different Denise. In accounts.
Talked to Santos.
It's the girl's parents.
Shut off the ADS.
You sure?
What's that?
That's the Aerial Deterrent System.
Keeps the airborne life away.
Why is it blinking?
Because dead ass Denise
in the Tower just turned it off.
We gotta get out
of this airspace right now.
That's another plane, right?
Not exactly.
- Is that a...?
- Quetzalcoatlus.
Late Cretaceous, should've stayed there.
Okay, okay.
It's cool. We're good. It's gone.
This plane in going down.
If you're gonna eject
you need to do it now.
I only got one chair, she's in it.
- You don't have parachutes?
- I wasn't expecting company.
Claire, we gotta get you off this plane.
What?
The parachute is gonna open automatically.
If it doesn't you pull this lever.
Do you understand me?
Claire! If it doesn't open automatically
you gotta pull this lever here
behind you, okay?
Ten thousand feet!
Hey! You're the one
who's gotta go get to her.
You're her mom. You're her only shot.
I'll see you again.
I love you.
What's the plan?
Whatever happens - that's the plan.
Three.
Alan, we need the code.
Let's try this thing.
Yeah.
Get down.
Thank God, it's you.
This place is such a maze.
We were so confused.
I thought we were straight up lost
Then you said Station 3.
And I was like, we thought...
Do you have the sample?
- What?
- What are you talking about?
The DNA sample, do you have it?
Biosyn's responsible
for the locusts epidemic.
Dodgson's covering it up.
You were right. I'm here to help you.
Do you have it?
Good.
This pod will take you
straight to the airfield.
We have a plane ready to fly.
Ian told you about Hexapod Allies?
No, I told him.
What?
- Okay, guys, gotta go.
- Wait.
Maisie.
Maisie Lockwood.
Go.
That was my baby.
Where'd you learn to fly?
Air Force.
Legacy on my mama side.
I'm Navy.
Okay, so how'd you end up doing this?
I was a legit contract pilot for a grip,
but didn't exactly pay enough
to be out here sending money home, ♪♪
so I hit up a few contacts
for the more lucrative shady shit.
Honestly, I might be done
with this line of work.
Is that why you're helping us?
I was there when they handed
your girl off to Biosyn.
I could've said something, but I didn't.
And when I saw her picture...
It isn't enough to do nothing.
Thank you.
No.
Nope.
What an asshole.
You good?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
I'm not shook at all. Are you?
No. No.
Ejection seat beacon. We'll find her.
Okay. Okay.
You really love her, huh?
Yeah.
I get it.
I like redheads too.
What? God.
- Who is that?
- That's Grant and Sattler.
- Is this live?
- Twelve minutes ago.
We were tracking the escaped asset.
My guys missed it.
They stole a DNA sample.
- How did they get in there?
- They used an access key.
Yankee white clearance.
One of our cameras saw Ian Malcolm
put something in Sattler's pocket.
All right. I wanna see him.
And get Ramsay up here too, will you?
Where are they now?
On the way to the airfield.
They caught a hyperloop right on schedule.
How are you?
You all right?
Not really, no.
Hey.
I knew your mom.
You did?
Yeah, few years after Hammond died
she came to my university to lecture.
And we became good friends.
What was she like?
Brilliant.
Light-years ahead of everybody else.
And she had a consciousness.
When they were building theme parks
she was determined to prove
that genetic power could save lives.
- And I was her experiment?
- No.
She wanted a child more than anything.
But she wanted you to have
what she couldn't,
a full life.
I didn't know her long,
but I know she loved you very much.
What's happening?
This must be the old amber mines.
They must've made access doors
when they built these tunnels.
Hey.
I heard the alarm. Everything all right?
Yeah, nothing we can't handle.
Listen...
You rang?
Oh, good, Dr. Malcolm, you are
fired.
What?
It was such a cushy gig.
You can give your access key
to security if you still have it.
One of the hyperloop pods
just shut down in the amber mines.
What?
Wow, this day.
Which pod?
Are there...
dinosaurs in the mines?
There are dinosaurs everywhere.
Technically birds are dinosaurs,
genetically speaking.
Lewis, Grant and Sattler are on this pod.
We need to send a security team out there.
Okay, absolutely, Ramsay, thank you.
Let's all just stay in our lanes though.
We can take care of it.
Thank you, Doctor.
That's it, huh? Nothing else to see here?
I'm not sure I admire your tone right now.
- You need to leave.
- Yeah, I do.
But first...
I owe all these folks an apology.
I think that by lending my cachet
to this joint
I might have made it seem
as if Biosyn wasn't rotten to the core.
- That's enough, Ian.
- See, that's how they get ya.
They give you so many promotions
in the short period of time.
That it bludgeons your capacity
for critical thinking.
Oh, my God.
So, then there are doors
that you don't open.
Things that you ignore.
But mainly, he's exploiting
your enchantment
with these.
Is there an actual concern here?
Or you just...
You are racing toward the extinction
of our species,
and you don't care.
You know exactly what you're doing.
But you won't stop.
You can't.
I thought you might be different,
but you just like everyone else.
You see what you wanna see.
You imagine unchecked avarice,
so that's what you find.
You envision what, an evil unbound
Prometheus, so that what I am to you?
Prometheus got gored.
So will you, you rapacious rat bastard.
Ramsay, would you help
Dr. Malcolm gather his things?
His room and then to the airfield.
That's it.
Dodgson.
Allosaurus?
Giganotosaurus.
Largest known terrestrial carnivore.
He put two apex predators in one valley.
Pretty soon there's only gonna be one.
Did you feel that?
That's an air current.
Must be an opening up ahead.
How old is this mine do you think?
Just breathe.
Nobody panic. Just watch out for bats.
- Who said anything about bats?
- I hate bats.
There's probably no bats.
No falling rocks.
Just a possibility of toxic gas,
dehydration, hypothermia.
Just possibilities, nothing for certain.
I should've left you where you were.
Why did I bring you into this?
You were happy in your element.
What?
- Ellie.
- What?
I wasn't happy.
You weren't?
Do you have kids?
What?
No. I do. Two.
But not with him?
No.
No, just old friends.
Yeah, just old friends.
Really?
Won't be long
before security knows you're gone.
Oh, map. That looks like an old map.
Do you have a new map?
There's an access gate
to the north-east corner of the mine.
- If your friends make it out.
- If?
When they make it out,
that's where they'll be.
These roads are protected, right?
Yeah, drive fast.
You did good.
Yeah, well... Actually,
it's a complete disaster, but thanks.
Not yet.
Watch yourself.
- Ellie.
- Yeah.
What was that?
Careful.
- Oh, my God!
- Are you okay?
Forget the hat!
Come on!
Go, go!
It's a car.
- God, Ian!
- In here! Over here.
- In here!
- Come on, Ian!
- Open the gate!
- Please help us.
Do you know the code?
I didn't know there was gonna be a code.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
The brake, pull the break!
There's 10,000 possibilities.
Push with your legs! That's it.
- 1984.
- Come on, Ian!
- Here come again!
- Hurry!
Miles Davis' birthday, 0526.
- Ian, do something!
- Please, please!
We're not gonna make it.
Let's all try and stay positive.
- Please.
- I know. I know.
Oh, my God!
What do you know,
it actually worked.
- Ian, this is Maisie.
- Hi, Maisie.
We got the DNA.
We need to get out of this valley.
- Yeah, let's go.
- Come on.
Come on, come on.
Go on! Get.
Hey.
Oh, my God.
I thought you were dead.
What do they even eat?
We better get inside.
LOCUST PLAGUE JUMPS CONTINENTS
WHERE DID THEY COME FROM?
Go ahead.
Containment chamber is compromised.
It's locked.
That'll need something heavy,
something sharp, or both.
That can't be right.
- Is that...?
- Oh, no.
Oh, my God.
He's burning the evidence.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
That's bananas.
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
I know how this may seem
precarious, but...
No, we're teetering.
Should we all
lean to the left or something?
That's a very constructive.
Thank you, Maisie.
Slow. Slow.
Slow.
We're fine.
See this?
This is fine.
Alan? Alan!
How's everybody?
It's my parents! Help!
Help!
Listen.
Oh, my God!
You're okay.
You came to get me.
You actually came to get me.
Of course we did, sweetheart.
- Hey, kiddo.
- Of course.
I remember you.
I remember you too.
They helped me escape.
You okay?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
We gotta go.
Gonna have to break the window
to get inside that thing.
Hope nobody's afraid of heights.
- Don't move.
What is that?
Giganotosaurus.
Biggest carnivore the world has ever seen.
Come on.
Maisie, look at me. Look at me.
Move.
- Go, go.
- Come on!
No, no!
- Hustle.
- I'm gonna die!
Climb. Climb, kid.
You're not. No, you're not. You're okay.
Go, go!
Come on.
Hey!
Oh, yeah, come here.
Hit me up.
I got ya.
Go, go!
Run!
See, not so bad.
Come on.
Claire!
Call in evacuation.
We need to bring the animals inside.
The regulations are clear
that in the event of a level...
Jeffrey.
Goddamn it!
Just...
Just call it.
Attention! Attention!
This is an immediate evacuation order.
Remote herding system is now active.
All living assets en route
to emergency containment.
I can't get hold of anybody
since everything is on fire.
- Dr. Sattler, get some water.
- Thanks.
Dr. Grant, yours.
I'm Owen Grady.
Big fan, I've read your book.
Well, book on tape.
Owen Grady. Owen Grady.
Yeah, I know who you are.
You trained Raptors.
I tried. Yeah.
- How are you doing?
- One here.
You were at Jurassic World.
Jurassic World?
Not a fan.
Okay, so, we're good
to find a way outta here?
Yep.
Let's get it.
There's a helicopter
out in the main complex.
We turn the ADS back on, we go home.
Wait, what's an ADS?
Aerial deterrent system.
You know, for the pterodactyls and shit.
Keeps them away from the helicopters.
How do we turn it back on?
Okay, it looks like all the systems
run through the control room
which is on the third floor,
And these outposts
are all connected underground.
All right, easy, Rambo.
So, you worked in the Raptor pan, huh?
Yeah.
Wow, and what happens, you just tell them
what to do and they comply or...
Well, that's a human-animal bond
based on mutual respect.
I had a dog once.
Humped my leg so much
I got a callus on my shinbone.
It's a true story.
Oh, God. Hey.
Good.
Here's what I'm thinking.
We get started again, you and me.
I can get money.
Yeah. Money's cheap these days.
What's the matter? Don't look so worried.
There's opportunity in everything,
even this.
You'll learn that.
I've been thinking...
Maybe you take more
of a lead now, okay?
You're ready I think.
Here. Take it.
What the hell is the matter with you?
It was you.
You told Malcolm about the program. You...
You set this whole thing up.
You set me up?
I gave you every opportunity
I did not have. I...
We have an understanding, Ramsay,
and you do not break that.
I would not break this.
I'm not you.
This is very bad.
This is the same system
we used at the park.
Great, so we can turn on the thing
and then we all get out of here?
Let me see. ADS
What's this? What's "Error 99"?
Not enough power.
In a breakdown all available power
is seized by the primary system
to keep running.
We need all that power
to re-activate the ADS.
So, the system safety feature
is what's gonna kill us?
Of course.
How do we get more power?
We can't. But we can re-distribute
what we have, if we just...
- Just need to...
- Shut down the primary system.
- Yes, exactly.
- Where is it?
- Next floor up.
- I'm coming with you.
We escaped down here.
Where is that? Water Treatment Center.
Hydroelectric system, Sub 8.
Give me eight minutes, I could find her.
- Wait, who's this now?
- Beta.
- Blue's baby.
- Velociraptor.
- What?
- A baby Raptor?
And you gave her a name, how about that.
I made a promise we would bring her home.
You made a promise to a dinosaur.
You're coming with us, right?
Maisie...
Please.
- We'll be on channel 5.
- Okay.
We're on 3.
Come back.
I always come back.
I'll have that chopper hot in ten,
wait for my signal.
Evacuation Phase Four complete.
All living assets are now in containment.
Come on.
Still get nightmares?
All of the time.
You?
I have a lot of regrets.
Oh, yeah?
Well...
We hold on to regret we stay in the past.
What matters, I guess, is...
Is what we do now, right?
Yeah.
Nobody said there'll be bugs.
B4. She's in here.
Watch the sides.
They always come from the sides.
You know, at first we thought...
they disembowel their prey, but now...
They're smart enough
to go straight to the throat.
Veins, the arteries.
Sometimes both at the same time.
Okay.
We've got you. It's right down that isle.
It's right down that isle where you are.
Why are they skulking?
You can sprint right for it.
Okay. Here it is.
Okay, it'll be a yellow button
on the grid of six.
There's a green button.
Do you see a green button?
It's not the green button,
it's fourth from the bottom.
Whoa, whoa...
Fourth one up?
Third one down or fourth one up.
Same thing.
Ian, be specific.
She was here.
Lights off.
I don't know how I could possibly
be more specific
other than to say that the one you want
is marked with E1.
- E1.
- Okay.
Yeah.
No. No, no.
Dammit, she's fast.
Hey!
Eyes on me!
I've gotta hit her
on the side of the neck.
Maisie, you gonna hold her focused.
Grant, we're triangulating.
Go.
Sorry, girl.
I promised your mama I'd get you home.
Primary system rebooting.
Wait, no, no.
It's rebooting.
No, it shouldn't be doing that.
Here, come on, take this.
Ian, shut it down!
We're gonna make it work.
We gonna figure this out.
- It's very complex.
- We don't have time for complex!
Primary system compromised.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Aerial deterrent system activate.
Victory. Victory.
Damn, that felt good.
Come on!
What's your story...
At Biosyn, we're dedicated to the idea
that dinosaurs can teach us
more about ourselves.
All right, Kayla, we're good to go.
Okay, cutie.
- You all right?
- Someday.
Hey.
I remember you.
Please, you have to listen to me.
You created an ecological disaster.
And I can fix it.
Charlotte Lockwood changed every cell
in Maisie's body.
It saved her life.
If I can understand how Charlotte
rewrote Maisie's DNA
I can spread change from one locust
to the entire swarm
before it's too late.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's what she would've wanted.
Thank you.
No, no, no.
No, no.
Him? Not him. Not him. It's always him.
Every single...
Is that a dinosaur on your shoulder?
Yeah, why?
I have air. Meet me in the center.
Wait, wait. Hey.
Do not land in here.
I don't have a choice, dude.
The valley isn't safe.
No, they're not in the valley anymore!
This isn't about us.
Get up! Come on, come on!
Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Ellie, no!
Go, Maisie, go!
Ramsay, get on.
Come on, come on.
Everybody hold on to somebody.
No, at every level.
Complete systemic corruption
in the executive ranks.
"Systemic corruption", you got that?
Write that down.
Yeah, okay.
And then we clashed
into this ice lake, right?
I mean they literally owe me a plane.
I need to get this sample vetted
at the lab
before I take it to my contract
at the Times.
You could a come with me.
Unless you need to get back to your dig.
- Ellie.
- Yeah?
I am coming with you.
I know.
One more minute, then we'll send you home
with your folks.
Today marks the first day of testimony
from Biosyn whistleblower Ramsay Cole.
The Senate will also hear
from doctors Grant, Sattler and Malcolm
who have been vocal on this debate
since the incident at Jurassic Park.
You look
- Untrustable.
- Trustworthy.
Yeah, not getting used to it.
Let's finish this.
Yeah.
Dr. Henry Wu has found an emergency
solution to the ecological crisis.
His use of a pathogen
to alter the locusts' DNA
has revolutionized modern genetics.
He attributed the discovery
to another scientist, Charlotte Lockwood,
who died nearly 13 years ago.
By UN decree Biosyn Valley
has been designated a global sanctuary.
The animals will live there free,
safe from the outside world.
Money?
- Money.
- Thank you.
Life on Earth has existed
for hundreds of millions of years.
And dinosaurs were only a part of that.
And we are an even smaller part of that.
They really put us in perspective.
The idea that life on Earth
existed 65 million years ago,
it's humbling.
We act like we're along here
but we're not.
We're a part of a fragile system
made up of all living things.
If we're going to survive
we'll have to trust each other.
Depend on each other.
Coexist.
Transcript by sub. Trader
Preuzeto sa www.titlovi.com